A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Education and Research Division (E&R), Program Files FA633
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Sol Chafkin Subject Files, 1972-1981; XXI
  - Grant Recommendations, 1978-1981 (Box 44)
  - Some Observations on Ford Foundation-supported CDCs and their Significance for Implementation of Government Policies and Programs, Oct 1977 (Box 44)
  - Mexican-American Organization Grants -- Evaluation, n.d. (Box 44)
  - Health, Nutrition and Population, Dec 1979 (Box 44)
  - Trip to Asia Reports, 1980 (Box 44)
  - Hispanic Papers, 1980 (Box 44)
  - Health, Nutrition and Population Seminar, 1979 (Box 44)
  - National Affairs Current Programs -- Background Comments and a Review, Nov 1, 1979 (Box 44)
  - Agricultural Cooperative Communities Correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 44)
  - Merrill S. Read, 1977-1978 (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals and Papers, 1972-1981 (Box 44)
  - James Comer, 1977 (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous Proposals and Reports, 1978 (Box 44)
- Ralph G. Bohrson Files, 1966-1970; XXII
  - Ralph G. Bohrson Subject Files -- Leadership Development Program, 1966-1970; XXII.1
    - Leadership Development Program (LDP) Brochure, 1968 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program -- History, 1968 (Box 45)
    - General Program Development -- Leadership Fellows Program, 1969 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Materials -- Incoming, 1969 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program -- Grant Awarding Procedure -- Letters and Forms, 1968 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program -- Inception and Development of Program, 1966-1967 (Box 45)
    - Staff -- Northeast -- 1st Year, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Selection Committee -- Northeast, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Selection Committee -- Southwest, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Correspondence -- Northeast -- 1st Year -- General Office Business, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Rev. Roger L. Albright, 1968 (Box 45)
    - Rejected Candidates Follow-up -- Northeast -- 1st Year, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Correspondence -- Southeast -- 1st Year -- General Office Business, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program -- Regional Characteristics and Related Programs -- Southeast, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Selection Committee -- Southeast, 1966-1967 (Box 45)
    - Staff -- Southeast -- 1st Year, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Gibson, Ben -- Consultant Leadership Fellows Program -- Southeast Region, 1966 (Box 45)
    - Staff -- Southwest -- 1st Year, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Correspondence -- Southwest -- 1st Year -- General Office Business (Box 45)
    - Sister Mary Denis Schwartz, RSM (Maine), 1967 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program Financial Policy/Practice, 1967 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program Mentor Relationship and Definitions, 1968 (Box 45)
    - Compilation of Statistical Materials, 1968-1970 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program -- Statistics, 1967-1969 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program -- Budget Data, 1967-1969 (Box 45)
    - Leadership Fellows Program -- Fellow's Address Directory, 1969 (Box 45)
  - Ralph G. Bohrson Subject Files, 1966-1967; XXII.2
    - Rural Education Improvement Conference -- Atlanta GA, Jul 17, 1967 (Box 53)
    - NCAI -- Conferences on Indian Affairs, 1967 (Box 53)
    - School Improvement Program -- Consultants Appointment Memoranda, 1967 (Box 53)
    - School Improvement Program -- Developmental Guidelines, 1966 (Box 53)
    - Staff Reports -- Public Education, 1967 (Box 53)
    - Urban Education -- Reorganization, 1966 (Box 53)
- Select Committee on the Future of Private and Independent Higher Education in New York State, 1966-1968; XXIII
  - Select Committee on the Future of Private and Independent Higher Education in New York State, 1966-1967 (Box 46)
  - Select Committee File, 1967-1968 (Box 46)
  - Select Committee on the Future of Private and Independent Higher Education in New York State -- Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous Notes -- Select Committee, 1967 (Box 46)
  - Mr. Bundy, 1967 (Box 46)
  - Letters and Press Release, 1967 (Box 46)
  - Select Committee Chronological Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 46)
  - Select Committee on the Future of Private and Independent Higher Education in New York State -- Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 46)
- Joshua L. Smith Correspondence Files, 1968-1970; XXIV
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1968 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1969 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-May 1970 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Jun 1970 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Jul 1970 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Aug 1970 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Sep 1970 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Oct 1970 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Nov 1970 (Box 47)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Dec 1970 (Box 47)
- Special Projects Grant Files, 1961-1970; XXV
  - Redlands, 1966-1968 (Box 48)
  - Furman University, 1968-1969 (Box 48)
  - Millsaps College, 1966-1969 (Box 48)
  - New York University, 1965-1970 (Box 48)
  - Wabash College, 1961 (Box 48)
  - Williams College, 1968 (Box 48)
  - Wellesley College, [1961-1970] (Box 48)
  - Whitman College 62-355, [1961-1970] (Box 48)
  - College of Wooster, [1961-1970] (Box 48)
  - Barnard College, [1961-1970] (Box 48)
  - Birmingham -- Southern College, [1961-1970] (Box 48)
  - Chicago University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - De Pauw University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Davidson College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Vanderbilt University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Trinity College, 1965-1968 (Box 48)
  - Tulane University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Vassar College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Oberlin College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Occidental College 62-349, 1962-1965 (Box 48)
  - Oklahoma City University 62-350, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - College of Saint Catherine, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Reed College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - St. Lawrence University 62-351, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - College of St. Thomas 62-352, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - St. Francis Xavier College 62-353, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - St. Louis University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - St. Olaf College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Smith College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - University of the South 62-354, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - University of Southern California 63-43, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Southwestern at Memphis, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Stanford University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - John B. Stetson University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Swarthmore College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Kalamazoo College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Knox College 62-345, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Lafayette College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Lake Forest College 62-346, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Lawrence University of Wisconsin 62-347, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Middlebury College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Mills College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Mount Holyoke College 62-348, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - University of Notre Dame, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Grinnell College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Hamilton College 62-344, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Cornell College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Denison University 62-342, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - University of Denver, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Earlham College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Emory University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Franklin and Marshall College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Goucher College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Amherst College 62-335, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Albion College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Antioch College 62-336, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Austin College 62-337, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Beloit College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Berea College 62-338, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Bowdoin College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Bryn Mawr College 62-339, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Brown University, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Carleton College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - The Claremont Colleges, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Coe College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Colgate College, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Colby College 62-340, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
  - Colorado College 62-341, 1961-1970 (Box 48)
- Peter E. de Janosi Subject Files, 1964-1967; XXVI
  - Rockefeller Fellowships in Economics 1917-1955, undated (Box 49)
  - Financing of Economic Research [NEGATIVES], 1966 (Box 49)
  - Ford Foundation -- Policies and Procedures -- Grant Actions, 1966-1967 (Box 49)
  - Churchill, Colin -- Hospital Research and Educational Trust, 1967 (Box 49)
  - Data Banks, Imformation, Retrieval, Etc., 1965 (Box 49)
  - Income Distribution, 1967 (Box 49)
  - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Jul 1967 (Box 49)
  - Liu, T.C. -- Cornell, 1967 (Box 49)
  - NBER Conference on Economics of Education (Schultz), 1966 (Box 49)
  - European Trip, Aug 1964 (Box 49)
  - Trip to Paris and London, Apr 1964 (Box 49)
  - International Seminar on Economics of Labor and Industrial Relations -- Ditchley Park, Oxfordshire, Apr 1964 (Box 49)
  - Brookings Meeting -- Washington DC, Dec 1965 (Box 49)
  - Hospital Journal Editorial Board, 1966 (Box 49)
  - Foundation Forums, 1967 (Box 49)
  - Europe, Mar 1967 (Box 49)
  - Europe -- Vienna -- General Information, Jun 1967 (Box 49)
  - London/Paris, Sep 1967 (Box 49)
  - Brookings Meeting, Mar 1967 (Box 49)
  - European Trip, 1965 (Box 49)
  - U.S. Academians Abroad -- Paper, 1966 (Box 49)
- Miscellaneous Files, 1966-1972; XXVII
  - 4 Day Week Task Force, 1972 (Box 50)
  - Ford Foundation -- Proposed Budget FY1971, Jun 1970 (Box 50)
  - Attitude Survey Concerning the Role of Women at the Ford Foundation, Dec 1970 (Box 50)
  - Some Observations -- Educational and Otherwise -- On the World Scene, 1968 (Box 50)
  - Hartford '74 Report to the Ford Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 50)
  - Documentation of Six Urban Teacher Training Programs -- Report to the Ford Foundation -- Appendices, Nov 15, 1969 (Box 50)
  - Bi-Lingual Studies, 1967 (Box 50)
  - Cleveland, OH -- Area Programs, 1967 (Box 50)
  - Community Development, 1966 (Box 50)
  - Computer-Assisted Instruction, 1967 (Box 50)
  - Criminal Institutions -- Rehabilitation Facets, 1966-1967 (Box 50)
  - Third International Cirriculum Conference -- Oxford, England, 1967 (Box 50)
  - Indian Education -- Various Agencies (1/2), 1966-1967 (Box 50)
  - Indian Education -- Various Agencies (2/2), 1967 (Box 50)
  - Mississippi Research and Development Center -- Dr. Kenneth Wagner, Director, 1967 (Box 50)
- Benjamin F. Payton Files, 1968-1981; XXVIII
  - Benjamin F. Payton Correspondence Files, 1972-1981; XXVIII.1
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Oct 1972 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Sep 1972 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Oct 1973 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Nov-Dec 1973 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1974 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1976 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Mar 1977 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Apr-Jul 1977 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Aug-Dec 1977 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Jun 1978 (Box 51)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jul-Dec 1978 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan-Jun 1979 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jul-Dec 1979 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Feb 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Mar 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Apr 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, May 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jun 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Aug 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Sep 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Oct 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Nov 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Dec 1980 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1980 (Box 52)
    - Alphabetical Correspondence File, 1981 (Box 52)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1981 (Box 52)
    - Minorities and Mathematics Conference, 1981 (Box 52)
    - CAEL -- Pending -- General, 1981 (Box 52)
    - Howard University -- Draft PRI, 1980 (Box 52)
    - Ford Foundation and Secondar Education of Minorities Program Review -- Outline, 1981 (Box 52)
    - General Reserve FY1980 (Box 52)
    - Ford Foundation -- No Student Aid Form Letter, [1978] (Box 52)
    - Keeton Report Correspondence, 1981 (Box 52)
    - Requests for Keeton Report, 1981 (Box 52)
    - Doctoral Fellowships -- Selection Committee Evaluations -- Black Americans, Mexican Americans, Native Americans and Puerto Ricans -- Attachment File -- 719-0021, 1971-1973 (Box 52)
    - Official Letters Advising Graduate Schools of the Transfer of Awardees to ETS and NFF -- 719-0021, 1974-1978 (Box 52)
  - Alphabetical Correspondence, 1980 (Box 53)
  - Kenneth Hudson, 1980 (Box 53)
  - The National Academy of Sciences (Commission on Human Resources), 1978-1979 (Box 53)
  - Blacks in Higher Education, 1977 (Box 53)
  - Plan of Operation -- Program for Support of Selected Black Colleges, 1973-1974 (Box 53)
  - Minorities and Mathematics Conference -- Reports, 1981 (Box 53)
  - Education Program of the Ford Foundation, Sep 1980 (Box 53)
  - Ford Foundation Minority Institutions Program -- Consoldated Operating and Financial Data, 1978 (Box 53)
  - Public Policy and Social Organization Program 1972-1979 -- Information Paper, Mar 1980 (Box 53)
  - The Ford Foundation and the Education of Minorities, Sep 1974 (Box 53)
  - Speeches -- Howard Howe II, 1980-1981 (Box 53)
  - Open University Conference on the Education of Adults at a Distance, Dec 1979 (Box 53)
  - Managing and Financing American Higher Education -- Information Paper, Dec 1977 (Box 53)
  - Education and Research Division -- Budget Alternatives for FY 1978-1979 -- Appendices, Mar 1977 (Box 53)
  - Benjamin F. Payton Conference Files, 1968-1980; XXVIII.2
    - Affirmative Action, 1973-1980 (Box 54)
    - Annual Conferences with Ford Foundation Staff and Black College Grantees -- Second Annual, Dec 1974 (Box 54)
    - Annual Conferences with Ford Foundation Staff and Black College Grantees -- Third Annual, 1976 (Box 54)
    - Annual Conferences with Ford Foundation Staff and Black College Grantees -- Atlanta Meeting, Mar 1977 (Box 54)
    - Annual Conferences with Ford Foundation Staff and Black College Grantees -- Atlanta Meeting, Jun 1974 (Box 54)
    - Meeting at Hampton VA, Apr 1977 (Box 54)
    - Annual Reports -- Ford Foundation, 1968-1978 (Box 54)
    - Armsey, James -- Issues, Needs Problems, 1974 (Box 54)
    - Atlanta University -- Paper for Trustees Meeting, 1977 (Box 54)
    - Atlanta University Center, 1978 (Box 54)
    - Benedict College, 1971 (Box 54)
    - Bishop College, 1979 (Box 54)
    - Black College Program -- Evaluation, 1976 (Box 54)
    - Black Scholars, 1975-1979 (Box 54)
    - Black Studies Reports, 1973 (Box 54)
    - Ralph Bohrson, 1976 (Box 54)
    - Boricua College -- PRI Action, 1979 (Box 54)
    - Boston University, 1980 (Box 54)
    - McGeorge Bundy, 1974-1979 (Box 54)
    - Carnegie Mellon Public Policy Program -- Comments on Report, 1979 (Box 54)
    - Commission on Black Higher Education, 1971-1972 (Box 54)
    - Commission on Higher Education for Blacks (Task Force Report), 1973 (Box 54)
    - Conference Re: The Problems of Minority Access to Higher Education, 1977 (Box 54)
    - Conference on Student Financial Assistance for Graduate Education, 1977 (Box 54)
    - Fifth Annual Ford Foundation Conference, 1978 (Box 54)
    - Meeting re: Survey of Minority Group Doctoral Recipients, 1977 (Box 54)
    - Conference on Higher Education and Affirmative Action re: Bakke Case, 1977 (Box 54)
    - Fifth Annual Ford Foundation Conference, 1978 (Box 54)
    - Meeting re: Institutional Coopertion to Increase Minority Students in Graduate Departments of Economics, 1977 (Box 54)
    - Conference re: Increasing Minority Ph.D. Candidates in Economics in Selected Research Institutions, 1977 (Box 54)
    - Conference on Minorities and Mathematics, 1980 (Box 54)
  - Benjamin F. Payton Subject Files, 1970-1981; XXVIII.3
    - Abel Amaya, 1975 (Box 55)
    - Native American in Los Angeles -- Final Report, Sep 1976 (Box 55)
    - American Indian Studies Center -- Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 55)
    - Equal Educational Opportunity Paper -- Draft, Aug 3, 1977 (Box 55)
    - Consolidated and Financial Data, 1977 (Box 55)
    - Four Minorities and the Ph.D. -- Ford Foundation Graduate Fellowships -- Report, Oct 1973 (Box 55)
    - Atlanta University Center Library -- Proposal, n.d. (Box 55)
    - Atlanta University Center -- Report, 1975 (Box 55)
    - Atlanta University Paper -- Final, Jun 1977 (Box 55)
    - Ford Foundation Minority Institutions Program -- Analyses of Operating and Financial Data, 1978 (Box 55)
    - Financial Analyses -- Atlanta University Center, 1977 (Box 55)
    - Atlanta University Center -- Comprehensive Plan, May 1976 (Box 55)
    - Dr. Samuel DuBois Cook, 1971 (Box 55)
    - Curriculum Vitae -- B.F. Payton, [1973] (Box 55)
    - DAP -- Budget File, 1977-1981 (Box 55)
    - Dyer, James -- Carnegie Corporation, 1973 (Box 55)
    - Education Division -- Future Programs, 1974-1980 (Box 55)
    - Education and Public Policy Committee -- Minutes, 1980 (Box 55)
    - Education and Public Policy Program -- Meeting with Frank Thomas (Higher Education for Minorities), 1979 (Box 55)
    - Education and Research -- Status Reports, 1977 (Box 55)
    - Education and Research -- Status Reports, 1977-1979 (Box 55)
    - Endowment Guidelines, 1976 (Box 55)
    - Equal Opportunity For Women -- Grants, 1973 (Box 55)
    - Fellowships, 1973 (Box 55)
    - TBI's -- Miscellaneous, 1972-1973 (Box 55)
    - Financial Aid Programs for Minorities -- Group Students in Law School, 1972 (Box 55)
    - Press Release -- TBI -- Letters from Congressmen, 1972 (Box 55)
    - News from the Ford Foundation -- Press Release re: Black College Grants, Oct 31, 1972 (Box 55)
    - Ford Foundation Letter -- Write-up on Black College Grants, Dec 15, 1972 (Box 55)
    - Ford Foundation Letter, 1975-1981 (Box 55)
    - Fromkin, Joseph -- Educational Status of Blacks 1960-1970, 1974 (Box 55)
    - Future of Ford Foundation, 1975 (Box 55)
    - Graduate Education and Black Americans, Nov 25, 1968 (Box 56)
    - Grants -- Legal Actions, 1972-1973 (Box 56)
    - Harnett-Payton Report -- Responses to, 1978 (Box 56)
    - Afro-American Religious Studies Review Committee, 1975 (Box 56)
    - Heard, Alexander, 1975-1980 (Box 56)
    - Henderson, Vivian, 1970-1975 (Box 56)
    - Health, Education and Welfare (HEW) -- Office of Education, 1976 (Box 56)
    - Health, Education and Welfare (HEW) and Private Black Colleges, 1978 (Box 56)
    - Higher Education for Under-Represented Minorities (FY1971-1972), 1970 (Box 56)
    - Higher Education Research Institute (HERI), 1978-1979 (Box 56)
    - Matthew Holden, 1972 (Box 56)
    - Howard University -- Joint Center for Political Studies (74-368), 1975 (Box 56)
    - Howard University Press, 1979 (Box 56)
    - Harold Howe, 1974-1979 (Box 56)
    - Roy Hudson, 1978-1979 (Box 56)
    - Immigration and Refugees, 1979 (Box 56)
    - Indian File, 1976 (Box 56)
    - Interim Report -- Private Black Colleges, 1976 (Box 56)
    - Clayton Johnson -- SUNY, 1973 (Box 56)
    - Vernon Jordan -- Urban League, 1975-1976 (Box 56)
    - Roger Kennedy, 1974 (Box 56)
    - Lavin, David E. -- Ethnicity and Equality, 1977 (Box 56)
    - Robert Leestma, 1976 (Box 56)
    - Walter Leonard, 1975 (Box 56)
    - Lewis, Professor Hylan, 1979 (Box 56)
    - Major Grantee Institutions, 1973 (Box 56)
    - Malcolm, Dr. S. -- Speech, n.d. (Box 56)
    - Meetings -- Pending -- Brookings on Desegregation of Higher Education, Jan 22, 1979 (Box 56)
    - Meetings -- Office of Education Personnel on CEFP, Oct 3, 1975 (Box 56)
    - Mexican-Americans -- Grants related to, 1973 (Box 56)
    - Miller, S.M. -- Positive Discrimination -- Some U.S. Experiences, 1973 (Box 56)
    - Middle East and Africa, 1975 (Box 56)
    - Minority Admissions and Performance in Graduate Education, 1977 (Box 56)
    - Ford Foundation -- Minority Fellowship Program -- A Midpoint Review, Feb 1976 (Box 56)
    - Minority Fellowship Program 1967-1974, Sep 1975 (Box 56)
    - Minorities Program -- Budget, 1972-1978 (Box 56)
    - Minorities Program -- Staff Meetings, 1973 (Box 56)
    - Minority Fellows with International Interests, 1975 (Box 56)
    - Minority Postdoctoral Fellowship Program -- Comments, 1979 (Box 56)
    - Minorities Program -- Personnel, 1973 (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 56)
    - Newsletters Announcing Ford Foundation Minority Program, 1971-1972 (Box 56)
    - Cornelia Palmer, 1973-1977 (Box 56)
    - Payton, B.F. -- An Interview -- Black Enterprise, Sep 1972 (Box 56)
    - Payton, B.F. -- New Trends in Civil Rights (Box 56)
    - Payton, B.F. -- Reaction of Civil Rights Leaders, n.d. (Box 56)
    - Payton, B.F. -- Reducing Minority Underrepresentation in Higher Education, 1977 (Box 56)
    - Payton, B.F. -- Black Colleges and Black Studies (Box 56)
    - Postdoctoral Fellowships -- Complaints, 1980 (Box 56)
    - Position Summaries, Feb 1981 (Box 56)
    - Posdoctoral Studies and U.S. Minorities -- Write up for Trustees, Dec 1978 (Box 56)
    - Rice, Lois D. -- Race, Poverty and the Colleges, 1978 (Box 57)
    - Riolo, Tony, 1974 (Box 57)
    - Scanlon-AUC Paper, 1976 (Box 57)
    - Site Visits, 1975-1976 (Box 57)
    - Site Visits, 1976-1977 (Box 57)
    - Status Report and DAP Status Report, 1980 (Box 57)
    - Stent, Madelon D., 1974 (Box 57)
    - Traditionally Black Institutions (TBI), 1972 (Box 57)
    - Title III AIDP, 1973 (Box 57)
    - Toward a Revised Program Emphasis for the Division of Education and Research of the Ford Foundation, Sep 1971 (Box 57)
    - Transom File, 1974 (Box 57)
    - Trueheart, William, 1977 (Box 57)
    - United Negro College Fund, 1980 (Box 57)
    - Urban Ed, Inc., 1973-1974 (Box 57)
    - Venture Fund, 1972-1974 (Box 57)
    - Veterans and Black Colleges, 1973 (Box 57)
    - Ward, H. -- Comments on E. Lincoln's Proposal -- Institute for the Study of African and Afro-American Religions (ISAAR), 1974 (Box 57)
    - Women -- Ford Foundation Programs, Oct 23, 1979 (Box 57)
    - Ambassador Andrew W. Young, 1977 (Box 57)
    - TBI -- Press Release, 1972 (Box 57)
    - Extra Copies of Materials for Feb 9th Meeting, 1977 (Box 57)
  - Benjamin F. Payton Report and Evaluation Files, 1970-1981; XXVIII.4
    - Program Budget Planning Paper FY 1980-1981, Mar 1979 (Box 58)
    - Programs to Improve the Quality of American Governance, Jun 1979 (Box 58)
    - Program Discussions for the Education and Public Policy Division in January, Nov 6, 1980 (Box 58)
    - The Ford Foundation and Higher Education -- A Review, Nov 1, 1973 (Box 58)
    - Towards Equal Opportunity in Higher Education, Mar 1974 (Box 58)
    - Ford Foundation Programs for Women -- Plans and Budgets for FY 1980-1981, Mar 1980 (Box 58)
    - Proposals for General Reserve Funding, Mar 27-28, 1980 (Box 58)
    - Ford Foundation's Program in the Changing Role of Women -- Information Paper, Mar 1973 (Box 58)
    - The Education Program of the Ford Foundation, Sep 1980 (Box 58)
    - The City University of New York -- Facilities, Finance and Governance, Dec 13, 1978 (Box 58)
    - Comments on Ways to Relate Title III to An Endowment Funding Plan, 1976 (Box 58)
    - Future Program -- Education and Research Division, Dec 1975 (Box 58)
    - The Ford Foundation and the Education of Minorities, Sep 1974 (Box 58)
    - The Ford Foundation and Higher Education -- Supplement to the Scanlon Report, Nov 8, 1973 (Box 58)
    - Current and Prospective Ford Foundation Interests in American Higher Education (Box 58)
    - Office for Southeast Asia Program Review Discussion Outline, Oct 30, 1980 (Box 58)